[
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER ONE \u2014SOVEREIGNTY OF THE PEOPLE AND?",
    "answer": "SUPREMACY OF THIS CONSTITUTION  \n1\u2014Sovereignty of the people.  \n2\u2014Supremacy of this Constitution.  \n3\u2014Defence of this Constitution...."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWO \u2014THE REPUBLIC?",
    "answer": "4\u2014Declaration of the Republic.  \n5\u2014Territory of Kenya.  \n6\u2014Devolution and access to services.  \n7\u2014National, official and other languages.  \n8\u2014State and religion.  \n9\u2014National symbols and national days.  \n10\u2014National values and principles of governance.  \n11\u2014Culture...."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THREE \u2014CITIZENSHIP?",
    "answer": "12\u2014Entitlements of citizens.  \n13\u2014Retention and acquisition of citizenship.  \n14\u2014Citizenship by birth.  \n15\u2014Citizenship by registration.  \n16\u2014Dual citizenship.  \n17\u2014Revocation of citizenship.  \n18\u2014Legislation on citizenship...."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOUR \u2014THE BILL OF RIGHTS?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO THE BILL OF RIGHTS  \n19\u2014Rights and fundamental freedoms.  \n20\u2014Application of Bill of Rights.  \n21\u2014Implementation of rights and fundamental freedoms.  \n22\u2014Enforcement of Bill of Rights.  \n23\u2014Authority of courts to uphold and enforce the  Bill of Rights.  \n24\u2014Limi..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FIVE \u2014LAND AND  ENVIRONME NT?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014LAND \n60\u2014Principles of land policy.  \n61\u2014Classification of land.  \n62\u2014Public land.  \n63\u2014Community land.  \n64\u2014Private land.  \n65\u2014Landholding by non -citizens.  \n66\u2014Regulation of land use and property.  \n67\u2014National Land Commission.  \n68\u2014Legislation on land.  \nPART 2\u2014 ENVIRONMENT AND NATURAL RE..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SIX \u2014LEADERSHIP AND INTEGRITY?",
    "answer": "73\u2014Respon sibilities of leadership.  \n74\u2014Oath of office of State officers.  \n75\u2014Conduct of State officers.  \n76\u2014Financial probity of State officers.  \n77\u2014Restriction on activities of State officers.  \n78\u2014Citizenship and leadership.  \n79\u2014Legislation to establish the ethics and a nti-corruption commis..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SEVEN \u2014REPRESENTATION OF THE PEOPLE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014ELECTORAL SYSTEM AND PROCESS  \n81\u2014General principles for the electoral system.  \n82\u2014Legislation on elections.  \n83\u2014Registration as a voter.  \n84\u2014Candidates f or election and political parties to comply with code of  \n        conduct.  \n85\u2014Eligibility to stand as an independent candidate.  \n86..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER EIGHT \u2014THE LEGISLATUR E?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014ESTABLISHMENT AND ROLE OF PARLIAMENT  \n93\u2014Establishment of Parliament.  \n94\u2014Role of Parliament.  \n95\u2014Role of the National Assembly.  \n96\u2014Role of the Senate.  \nPART 2\u2014COMPOSITION AND MEMBERSHIP OF PARLIAMENT  \n97\u2014Membership of the National Assembly.  \n98\u2014Members hip of the Senate.  \n99\u2014Qualifi..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER NINE \u2014THE EXECUTIVE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014PRINCIPLES AND STRUCTURE OF THE NATIONAL EXECUTIVE  \n129\u2014Principles of executive authority.  \n130\u2014The National Executive.  \nPART 2\u2014THE PRESIDENT AND DEPUTY PRESIDENT  \n131\u2014Authority of the President.  \n132\u2014Functions of the President.  \n133\u2014Power of mercy.  \n134\u2014Exerci se of presidential power..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TEN \u2014JUDICIARY?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014JUDICIAL AUTHORITY AND LEGAL SYSTEM  \n159\u2014Judicial authority.   \n160\u2014Independence of the Judiciary.  \n161\u2014Judicial offices and officers.  \n162\u2014System of courts.  \nPART 2\u2014SUPERIOR COURTS  \n163\u2014Supreme Court.  \n164\u2014Court of Appeal.  \n165\u2014High Court.  \n166\u2014Appointment of Chief Justice, Deputy Ch..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER ELEVEN \u2014DEVOLVED GOVERNMENT?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014OBJECTS A ND PRINCIPLES OF DEVOLVED GOVERNMENT  \n174\u2014Objects of devolution.  \n175\u2014Principles of devolved government.  \nPART 2\u2014COUNTY GOVERNMENTS  \n176\u2014County governments.  \n177\u2014Membership of county assembly.  \n178\u2014Speaker of a county assembly.  \n179\u2014County executive committees.  \n180\u2014Election..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWELVE \u2014PUBLIC FINANCE?",
    "answer": "PART I\u2014PRINCIPLES AND FRAMEWORK OF PUBLIC FINANCE  \n201\u2014Principles of public finance . \n202\u2014Equitable sharing of national revenue.  \n203\u2014Equitable share and other financial laws.  \n204\u2014Equalisation Fund.  \n205\u2014Consultation on financial legislation affecting counties.  \nPART 2\u2014OTHER PUBLIC FUNDS  \n20..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THIRTEEN \u2014THE PUBLIC SERVICE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014VALUES AND PRINCIPLES OF PUBLIC SERVICE  \n232\u2014Values and principles of public service.  \nPART 2\u2014THE PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION  \n233\u2014The Public Service Commission.  \n234\u2014Functions and  powers of the Public Service Commission.  \n235\u2014Staffing of county governments.  \n236\u2014Protection of public off..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOURTEEN \u2014NATIONAL SECURITY?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014NATIONAL SECURITY ORGANS  \n238\u2014Principles of national security.  \n239\u2014National security organs.  \n240\u2014Establishment of the National Security Council.  \n\n--- Page 10 ---\n\nConstitution of Kenya, 2010  \n 10 \nPART 2\u2014THE KENYA DEFENCE FORCES  \n241\u2014Establishment of Defence Forces and Defence Counci..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FIFTEEN \u2014COMMISSIONS AND INDEPENDENT?",
    "answer": "OFFICES  \n248\u2014Application of Chapter.  \n249\u2014Objects, authority and funding of commissions and independent  \n          offices.  \n250\u2014Composition, appointment and terms of office.  \n251\u2014Removal from office.  \n252\u2014General functions and powers.  \n253\u2014Incorporation of commissions and independent offices..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SIXTEEN \u2014AMENDMENT OF THIS CONSTITUTION?",
    "answer": "255\u2014Amendment of this Constitution.  \n256\u2014Amendment by parliamentary initiative.  \n257\u2014Amendment by popular initiative...."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SEVENTEEN \u2014GENERAL PROVISIONS?",
    "answer": "258\u2014Enforcement of this Constitution.  \n259\u2014Construing this Constitution.  \n260\u2014Interpretation...."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER EIGHTEEN \u2014TRANSITIONAL AND CONSEQUENTIAL?",
    "answer": "PROVIS IONS  \n261\u2014Consequential legislation.  \n262\u2014Transitional and consequential provisions.  \n263\u2014Effective Date.  \n264\u2014Repeal of previous constitution.  \nSCHED ULES \nFirst Schedule   Counties  \nSecond Schedule  National symbols  \nThird Schedule   National Oaths and affirmations  \n\n--- Page 11 ---..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER ONE \u2014SOVEREIGNTY OF THE PEOPLE AND?",
    "answer": "SUPREMACY OF THIS CONSTITUTION  \nSovereignty of the people.  \n1. (1) All sovereign power belongs to the people of Kenya and \nshall be exercised only in accordance with this Constitution.  \n \n(2) The people may exercise their sovereign power either directly \nor through their democratically elected re..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWO \u2014THE REPUBLIC?",
    "answer": "Declaration of the Republic.  \n4. (1) Kenya is a sovereign Republic.  \n \n(2) The Republic of Kenya shall be a multi -party democratic State \nfounded on the national values  and principles of governance referred \nto in Article 10.  \nTerritory of Kenya.  \n5. Kenya consists of the territory and territo..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THREE \u2014CITIZENSHIP?",
    "answer": "Entitlements of citizens.  \n12. (1) Every citizen is entitled to \u2014 \n(a) the rights, privileges and benefits of citizenship, subject to the \nlimits provided or permitted by this Constitution; and  \n(b) a Kenyan passport and any document of registration or \nidentification issued by the State to c itiz..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOUR \u2014THE BILL OF RIGHTS?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO THE BILL OF RIGHTS  \nRights and fundamental freedoms.  \n19. (1) The Bill of Rights is an integral part of Kenya\u2019s democratic \nstate and is the framework for social, economic and cultural policies.  \n \n(2) The purpose of recognising and protecting human rights an..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FIVE \u2014LAND AND  ENVIRONMENT?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014LAND \nPrinciples of land policy.  \n60. (1) Land in Kenya shall be held, used and managed in a \nmanner that is equita ble, efficient, productive and sustainable, and in \naccordance with the following principles \u2014 \n(a) equitable access to land;  \n(b) security of land rights;  \n(c) sustainable a..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SIX \u2014LEADERSHIP AND INTEGRITY?",
    "answer": "Responsibilities of leadership.  \n73. (1) Authority assigned to a State officer \u2014 \n(a) is a public trust to be exercised in a manner that \u2014 \n (i) is consistent with the purposes and objects of this \nConstitution;  \n(ii) demonstrates respect for the people;  \n(iii) brings honour to the nation and dig..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SEVEN \u2014REPRESENTATION OF THE PEOPLE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014ELECTORAL SYSTEM AND PROCESS  \nGeneral principles for the electoral system.  \n81. The electoral system shall comply w ith the following \nprinciples \u2014 \n(a) freedom of citizens to exercise their political rights under \nArticle 38;  \n(b) not more than two -thirds of the members of elective publi..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER EIGHT \u2014THE LEGISLATURE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014ESTABLISHMENT AND ROLE OF PARLIAMENT  \nEstablishment of Parliament.  \n93. (1) There is established a Parliament of Kenya, which shall \nconsist of the National Assembly and the Senate.  \n \n(2) The National Assembly and the Senate shall perform their \nrespective functions in accordance with t h..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER NINE \u2014THE EXECUTIVE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014PRINCIPLES AND STRUCTURE OF THE NATIONAL EXECUTIVE  \nPrinciples of executive authority.  \n129. (1) Executive authority derives from the people of Kenya \nand shall be exerc ised in accordance with this Constitution.  \n \n(2) Executive authority shall be exercised in a manner compatible \nwith th..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TEN \u2014JUDICIARY?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014JUDICIAL AUTHORITY AND LEGAL SYSTEM  \nJudicial authority.  \n159. (1) Judicial authority is derived from the people and vests in, \nand shall be exercised by, the courts and tribunals established by or \nunder this Constitution.  \n \n(2) In exercising judicial authority, the courts and tribunals ..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER ELEVEN \u2014DEVOLVED GOVERNMENT?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014OBJECTS AND PRINCIPLES OF DEVOLVED GOVERNMENT  \nObjects of devolution.  \n174. The objects of the devolution of government are \u2014 \n(a) to promote democratic and accounta ble exercise of power;  \n(b) to foster national unity by recognising diversity;  \n(c) to give powers of self -governance to t..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWELVE \u2014PUBLIC FINANCE?",
    "answer": "PART I\u2014PRINCIPLES AND FRAMEWORK OF PUBLIC FINANCE  \nPrinciples of p ublic finance.  \n201. The following principles shall guide all aspects of public \nfinance in the Republic \u2014 \n(a) there shall be openness and accountability, including public \nparticipation  in financial matters;  \n(b) the public fin..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THIRTEEN \u2014THE PUBLIC SERVICE?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014VALUES AND PRINCIPLES OF PUBLIC SERVICE  \nValues and principles of public service.  \n232. (1) The valu es and principles of public service include \u2014 \n(a) high standards of professional ethics;  \n(b) efficient, effective and economic use of resources;  \n(c) responsive, prompt, effective, impar..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOURTEEN \u2014NATIO NAL SECURITY?",
    "answer": "PART 1\u2014NATIONAL SECURITY ORGANS  \nPrinciples of national security.  \n238. (1) National security is the protection  against internal and \nexternal threats to Kenya\u2019s territorial integrity and sovereignty, its \npeople, their rights, freedoms, property,  peace, stability and prosperity, \nand other nati..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FIFTEEN \u2014COMMISSIONS AND INDEPENDENT?",
    "answer": "OFFICES  \nApplication of Chapter.  \n248. (1) This Chapter applies to the commissions specified in \nclause (2) and the independent offic es specified in clause (3), except \nto the extent that this Constitution provides otherwise.  \n \n(2) The commissions are \u2014 \n\n--- Page 150 ---\n\nConstitution of Kenya..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SIXTEEN \u2014AMENDMENT OF THIS CONSTITUTION?",
    "answer": "Amendment of this Constit ution.  \n255. (1) A proposed amendment to this Constitution shall be \nenacted in accordance with Article 256 or 257, and approved in \naccordance with clause (2) by a referendum, if the amendment relates \nto any of the following matters \u2014 \n(a) the supremacy of thi s Constitu..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SEVENTEEN \u2014GENERAL PROVISIONS?",
    "answer": "Enforcement of this Constitution.  \n258. (1) Every person has the right to institute court proceedings, \nclaiming that this Constitution has been contravened, or is threatened \nwith contravention.  \n \n(2) In addition to a person acting in their own interest, court \nproceedings under clause (1) may b..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER EIGHTEEN \u2014TRANSITIONAL AND CONSEQUENTIAL?",
    "answer": "PROVISIONS  \nConsequential legislation.  \n261. (1) Parliament shall enact any legislation required by this \nConstitution to be enacted to govern a particular matter within the \nperio d specified in the Fifth Schedule, commencing on the effective \ndate.  \n \n(2) Despite clause (1), the National Assemb..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWO\u2014REPUBLIC?",
    "answer": "Legislation in respect of culture (Arti cle 11 (3))  Five years..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THREE \u2014CITIZENSHIP?",
    "answer": "Legislation on citizenship (Article 18)  One year..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOUR\u2014THE BILL OF RIGHTS?",
    "answer": "Freedom of the media (Article 34)  Three years  \nFamily (Article 45)  Five years  \nConsumer protection (Article 46)  Four yea rs \nFair administrative action (Article 47)  Four years  \nFair hearing (Article 50)  Four years  \nRights of persons detained, held in custody or detained (Article \n51) Four y..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SIX\u2014LEADERSHIP AND INTEGRITY?",
    "answer": "Ethics and anti -corruption commission (Article 79)  One year  \nLegislation on leadership (Article 80)  Two years..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER SEVEN \u2014REPRESENTATION OF THE  PEOPLE?",
    "answer": "Legislation on elections (Article 82)  One year  \nElectoral disputes (Article 87)  One year  \nIndependent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (Article 88)  One year  \n\n--- Page 178 ---\n\nConstitution of Kenya, 2010  \n 178 \nChapter and Article  Time \nSpecification  \nLegislation on political parties (A..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER EIGHT\u2014THE LEGISLATURE?",
    "answer": "Promotion of represen tation of marginalised groups (Article 100)  Five years  \nVacation of office of member of Parliament (Article 103)  One year  \nRight of recall (Article 104)  Two years  \nDetermination of questions of membership of Parliament (Article \n105) Two years  \nRight to pet ition Parliam..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER NINE\u2014EXECUTIVE?",
    "answer": "Power of mercy (Article 133)  One year  \nAssumption of office of president (Article 141)  Two years..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TEN\u2014JUDICIARY?",
    "answer": "System of courts (Article 162)  One year  \nRemoval from office (Arti cle 168)  One year  \nJudiciary Fund (Article 173)  Two years  \nVetting of judges and magistrates (Sixth schedule, Section 23)  One year..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER ELEVEN \u2014DEVOLVED GOVERNMENT?",
    "answer": "Speaker of a county assembly (Article 178)  One year  \nUrban areas and cities (Article 18 3) One year  \nSupport for county governments (Article 190)  Three years  \nRemoval of a county governor (Article 181)  18 months  \nVacation of office of member of county assembly (Article 194)  18 months  \nPubli..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER TWELVE \u2014PUBLIC FINANCE?",
    "answer": "Revenue Fu nds for county governments (Article 207)  18 months  \nContingencies Fund (Article 208)  One year  \n\n--- Page 179 ---\n\n       Constitution of Kenya, 2010  \n 179 \nChapter and Article  Time \nSpecification  \nLoan guarantees by national government (Article 213)  One year  \nFinancial control (A..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER THIRTEEN \u2014PUBLIC SERVICE?",
    "answer": "Values and principles of public service (Article 232)  Four years..."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the summary of CHAPTER FOURTEEN \u2014NATIONAL SECURITY?",
    "answer": "National security organs (Article 239)  Two years  \nCommand of the National Police Service (Article 245)  Two years  \nGENERAL   \nAny other legislation required by this Constitution  Five years  \n \n \nSIXTH  SCHEDULE                      (Article 262) \n \nTRANSITIONAL AND CONSEQUENTIAL PROVISIONS  \nPAR..."
  }
]